<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Embedded, Linux, RISC-V blog</title>
    <link>https://romeus.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Embedded, Linux, RISC-V blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://romeus.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on My FOSDEM 2026 Presentation</title>
      <link>https://romeus.github.io/post/fosdem_reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://romeus.github.io/post/fosdem_reflection/</guid>
      <description>Hi everybody,&#xA;The video of my presentation is now available on its permanent page:&#xA;Reproducing Linux Kernel Bugs in 5 Minutes with virtme-ng&#xA;https://fosdem.org/2026/schedule/event/99ULYW-repro-linux-kernel-bug-5-min-virtme-ng/ I would like to share a more detailed reflection on the presentation itself. I believe we should be our own toughest critics, and I hope the lessons I learned will be useful both for me and for others preparing for future conferences.&#xA;There is a saying:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Kernel Mentorship program graduation</title>
      <link>https://romeus.github.io/post/lkmp_graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:36:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://romeus.github.io/post/lkmp_graduation/</guid>
      <description>It was a long journey. I heard about Linux Kernel Mentorship Program in the mid of the January, went through the application process and was selected as a mentee. Despite I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a newbie kernel developer, I learnt a lot during my mentorship period. And now, this journey is over and I am graduated.&#xA;I want to thank my wonderful and patient Linux Foundation mentors and experienced kernel developers and maintainers - Shuah Khan, Javier Carrasco Cruz and Julia Lawall from the bottom of my heart for their support, wise and passion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://romeus.github.io/post/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 12:08:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://romeus.github.io/post/whoami/</guid>
      <description>$ whoami Passionate Linux Kernel and userspace developer enabling cutting-edge Intel® RDT HW for the upcoming Cloud-targeted Intel® Xeon® CPUs, for the wide range of capabilities from traditional CMT, CAT and MBA to the newest I/O RDT, SNC, CBA, etc.. and having a good knowledge of resctrl and the resctrl2 filesystems internals.&#xA;Embedded and firmware developer having experience with Yocto, Buildroot, U-Boot, etc.., running this stack both in virtualized environments like QEMU/KVM, and in custom ARM and RISC-V based hardware boards.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
